<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Government | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/categories/government/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T21:23:21+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Of Piracy and Social Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2007/05/21/of-piracy-and-social-service/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-21T07:06:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2007/05/21/of-piracy-and-social-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Take a look at this!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.channelregister.co.uk/2007/05/18/indian_tech_vendors_protest_microsoft/">http://www.channelregister.co.uk/2007/05/18/indian_tech_vendors_protest_microsoft/</a></p>

<p>One of the many WTFs you get once in a while in the tech world. Apparently PC dealers are on a state wide bandh after getting notices from Microsoft for Piracy. And these guys are claiming that they are doing a &ldquo;service&rdquo; to the community by installing illegitimate copies of Windoze.</p>

<p>SITA or South Gujarat Information Technologists Association says, &ldquo;"Since we are are not charging anything extra for installing the software, it means that we are actually not trading in pirated software. For us this is just a sewa (selfless act) that we are offering to our customers. Besides, the pricing of their operating systems is way too high for the Indian markets.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yup, while I agree about the pricing of M$ products..And keeping their &ldquo;Ethics&rdquo; (or the lack of it) aside, I somehow feel for M$. Whatever said, Software Piracy is akin to stealing stuff and theres no way you can defend yourself by telling that you are a doing a god damn frigging &ldquo;sewa&rdquo;. Piracy is so rampant that people think that Windoze comes free with their computers. And an association that exists, supporting these Pirates, sheesh!. If you cant afford a software, buy or use something thats Free or costs less. And even if you are using a illegitimate copy of something, just dont fucking go around telling people that you are part of a great liberation revolution or worse, claim that you are doing service to the community by distributing them.</p>

<p>Wondering, if a day will come when pimps will roam around telling that they are doing a &ldquo;sewa&rdquo; to the public. Its high time the Government steps in and stop these guys. (I do my bit when someone asks me to install winxp, I ask them to STFU.)</p>

<p>And my evil mind says that I should try it as a prank on local computer dealers.</p>

<p>And if you are someone I know and have a problem in your wretched boxes, FUCK OFF! I WONT FIX IT unless its running GNU/Linux or something legally bought.</p>

<p>Man, am I feeling a sudden urge to skin these people alive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BSNL bonanza or ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2006/12/25/bsnl-bonanza-or/"/>
    <updated>2006-12-25T11:01:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2006/12/25/bsnl-bonanza-or</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BSNL has claimed that they will upgrade all the 256k connections to 2mbps..Juicy&hellip;</p>

<p>One thing puzzling me though is the fact that I have a 900UL connection. Anyone with some other plan with a 2 Mbps connection has to be mental&hellip;..For example, 500 bucks per month entitles you for a free 1024 mb usage&hellip;2 Mbps with 1024megs is nothing. If you are applying for a BSNL connection, stay clear out of this plan. Its puny&hellip;For example,</p>

<p>256 kbps =  32 kBps (B &ndash;> Bytes, b &ndash;> bits, this is what everyone advertise)&hellip;</p>

<p>So..Lets suppose you download a big file for an hour..In an hour there are 60 minutes and hence 60 * 60 = 3600 sec&hellip;So if you were to download something for an hour you would have downloaded 3600*32 =  115200 kBs or 115.2 MBs&hellip;.This is for 1 hour with a 256 kbps..So around some 9 hours you are done&hellip;.Yeah but of course you still have those night unlimited slots&hellip;.</p>

<p>Now 2mbps = 4 * 256 kbps => 4 * 32kBps =  128kBps! (Boys thats fast)&hellip;That means you will use your 1024 megs quota in just  2 &frac12; hours&hellip;(excluding the free night usage)&hellip;</p>

<p>With an 900 UL plan there aint any limitations and this is what scares me..2 Mbps with an unlimited connection for 900 bucks is a godsend, really economical&hellip;But I have a sneaky feeling that the current 900 UL plan would be left out, forcing the heavy users to switch to other plans&hellip;GOtta save money if that happens..</p>

<p><strong>UPDATE:</strong></p>

<p>Bsnl, sneaky chums have cleanly excluded UL plans outta this&hellip; here <a href="http://chennai.bsnl.co.in/News/BBSTariff010107.htm">http://chennai.bsnl.co.in/News/BBSTariff010107.htm</a></p>

<p>The troubling thought is that, all are capped&hellip;and they are low&hellip;another thing is to note the &ldquo;upto&rdquo; word in the table except the Home 3300 plan. I think I will play safe and go with the present 900 UL&hellip;.I download around 10 gigs per month btw&hellip;none of those plans seems attractive&hellip;</p>

<p>Another year,  another disappointment&hellip;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Monsoon...the good, the bad and the worse]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2006/10/28/monsoonthe-good-the-bad-and-the-worse/"/>
    <updated>2006-10-28T17:11:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2006/10/28/monsoonthe-good-the-bad-and-the-worse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Chennai is not particularly known for its pleasant weather..I know why.
Its either the heat or the water..yes, water especially during the monsoons.</p>

<p><strong>The Good</strong>
I like the heavy rains for two reasons. One, it ensures that the price of the water will still stay below that of crude oil for the rest of the year; Two, Holidays..Ahh..its blissful to wake up early in a monday morning, the sight of dark gloomy clouds bringing rain like anything, and the morning news bringing the news that its &ldquo;holiday today&rdquo;&hellip;Hmmm..Nothing like bunking classes for a valid reason..:D</p>

<p><strong>The Bad</strong>
The roads..Roads here are so bad that its too &ldquo;dangerous&rdquo; even for rally cars. And the North East Monsoon just makes it worse..:s..I live in a low lying area and the road has now become a fishing pond with everyone blocking the way with their fishing poles and worse, it is the site of the amphibian love making in the night..I would say a field trip for the zoologists (I love animals myself, but croaking noises when you are dreaming about owning a cray3 is bit too far for me).</p>

<p><strong>The Worse</strong>
This is what really pisses me off..Everything around me is sticky and wet..My mom was mocking the whole day today that I need diapers when I sleep..Right now my bed is having a bright canary yellow bed cover that reminds me off eastman coloured movies, just because my usual favourite green one is damp&hellip;And believe me I didnt do it..Also the keyboard is sticky, and coding with a sticky keys and a mushy mouse has become a PITA</p>

<p>Hmmm..Just wondering what the blokes at my college hostel are doing&hellip;Their situation must be really FUBAR&rsquo;d since they live in an amphibian love making site throughout the year..:D</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
