<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Tips | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/categories/tips/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T21:16:39+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save your staplers!]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2011/02/06/save-your-staplers/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-06T15:45:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2011/02/06/save-your-staplers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Picture this. You are at work on a Friday evening. You are all pumped up! Who wouldn&rsquo;t be. Two full days of zero work ahead! You shutdown your computer, rise up, turn around to leave and BAM! This happens,</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/office-space.jpg">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/office-space.jpg</a>"></p>

<p>The key to &lsquo;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Lumbergh">Lumberg Evasion</a>&rsquo; is not only to stay &lsquo;hidden&rsquo; but also to be aware of your boss' whereabouts. Information is wealth and can potentially save your weekend.</p>

<p>I wanted to check out Pygame and hacked out a little python script which does this. The idea is that you position your webcam (el-cheapo-no-brand webcams sell for peanuts) near your cubicle/desk and get notified if there is some movement in a predefined area. Also works great if you have a laptop and want to know if someone is peeking over your shoulder (yeah, yeah&hellip; I know about mirrors).</p>

<p>The script can detect movements within the red rectangle. Here is how it does this</p>

<ul>
<li><p>When we start the script, the average color within the red rectangle is determined. This will act as the reference color.</p></li>
<li><p>Deviations in this average color is monitored in consecutive frames. If its more than a certain threshold, there is some movement.</p></li>
<li><p>When this happens, play a sound and pop up a little notification</p></li>
</ul>


<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-22.png">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-22.png</a>"></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-21.png">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-21.png</a>"></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-211.png">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/screenshot-211.png</a>"></p>

<p>Of course, it goes without saying that its just a simple hack. Works well if the background color is of an uniform color.</p>

<p>P.S: No, I don&rsquo;t work for an &lsquo;Initech&rsquo;.</p>

<p>P.P.S: If you are one of those &lsquo;Bill Lumberg&rsquo; types, Fuck you!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[simplejson's simple gotcha]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/09/17/simplejsons-simple-gotcha/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-17T18:30:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/09/17/simplejsons-simple-gotcha</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like simple things. Anything more complex more than &lsquo;simple&rsquo; is tough to deal with. Therefore it comes as no surprise that I love JSON. Heck, the entire grammar fits in a business card.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2551/3763158824_e2f57810c4.jpg">http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2551/3763158824_e2f57810c4.jpg</a>"></p>

<p>If you take a closer look at the spec above, you will notice that the keys for a JSON &lsquo;dictionary&rsquo; should be strings. I have a feeling that programmers like me whose language-of-mass-destruction is python are likely to overlook this minor gotcha.</p>

<p>This is where it gets interesting. Python&rsquo;s json module tries to do something smart when you try to encode a python dictionary into a JSON string. In this case, all the keys are python ints.</p>

<p><code>
In [3]: json.dumps({ 1 : 'Foo', 3: 'Baz'})
Out[3]: '{"1": "Foo", "3": "Baz"}'
</code></p>

<p>When I decode it back to a python object&hellip;</p>

<p><code>
In [4]: json.loads(json.dumps({ 1 : 'Foo', 3: 'Baz'}))
Out[4]: {u'1': u'Foo', u'3': u'Baz'}
</code></p>

<p>BAM! The json module silently converts all my integer keys to strings. I, for one, would have preferred an Exception to be raised instead.</p>

<p>Something like this, for example.
<code>
In [19]: class F: pass
...
In [20]: f = F()
In [21]: json.loads(json.dumps({ f : 'Foo', 3: 'Baz'}))
... snip errors ...
TypeError: key &lt;__main__.F instance at 0x92b4b2c&gt; is not a string
</code></p>

<p>In this case, I get the desired behaviour where a &lsquo;TypeError&rsquo; is raised. Stupid example, but you get the idea.</p>

<p>If I am missing something obvious here please do comment. This particular cheekiness of the json module caught me unawares recently. Or maybe I was wrong in expecting the decode operation to return something that is identical to the source.</p>

<p>Interestingly, the json support modules that ship with TurboGears error out if you try to return a dictionary having non-string keys from your controller methods.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Touring, now a Breeze! ]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/07/18/touring-now-a-breeze/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-18T16:58:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/07/18/touring-now-a-breeze</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>India, is a wonderful place for touring on a motorbike. With terrains ranging from high mountainous North, North Eastern India to the Coastal plains and lush Ghats down South, we sure have a huge load of places to see and experience. Motorbike touring can also be risky since a disproportionate rate of road accidents involve two-wheelers. Therefore it is absolutely necessary for the rider to protect himself on the road with proper riding gears.</p>

<p>The ideal mode of getting riding gear would be to look for clearance sales outside our country and ask the relatives or friends to ship it down to India for us. For people like me, whom the relatives <em>hate</em> to be related to, there are local players like <a href="http://cramster.in">Cramster</a> and <a href="http://planetdsg.com">DSG</a> who provide gear that are priced competitively. I already have a nice helmet but the lack of a proper armoured touring jacket was preventing me from getting adventurous enough to go out on long road trips.</p>

<h4>Requirements</h4>

<p>I wanted a jacket that that could satisfy all the following requirements.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Should be made of a fabric that doesn&rsquo;t tear easily protecting me against scraping injuries.</p></li>
<li><p>Armor in the joints and some padding in the back for protection against hard falls.</p></li>
<li><p>Since Chennai is not blessed with a good weather, the Jacket shouldn&rsquo;t boil me alive when I am wearing it. Should be bearable in hot weather atleast when the bike is in motion.</p></li>
<li><p>Extra brownie points for usability in the rains.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Alpinestars are great but they are simply too expensive for me. <a href="http://www.planetdsg.com/">DSG</a> distributes them in India in case you have saved enough moola to buy one. Be wary of fake imitation Alpinestars gear that are sold here in Chennai for 5 &ndash; 6k. They look genuine but they are, at the end of the day; fake.</p>

<h4>Narrowing down the choices:</h4>

<p><a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsg-maze-jacket-black.jpg"><img src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsg-maze-jacket-black.jpg?w=300" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>Taking into account all these and reading user posts from <a href="http://xbhp.com/talkies">xBHP</a> (in addition to rabid googling), I shortlisted DSG Maze and the <a href="http://www.cramster.in/ridinggear.php">Cramster</a> Breezer 2.0. Earlier, I had almost decided to order Maze online, but after seeing the Cramster in action during the <a href="http://www.xbhp.com/talkies/458471-post4443.html">Vedanthangal xBHP G2G</a>, I noticed that the Cramster Breezer 2.0 qualified  as a worthy competition to the more expensive Maze, both of which met my requirements except for the usability in the rains. Also the presence of Leather shoulders and cuffs in Maze was putting me off. They are damn cool and sexy, but leather doesn&rsquo;t go well with rain. To add to the confusion of choices, I learnt that Cramster had released a new all black Breezer 3.0 phasing out the 2nd revision.</p>

<p>The presence of a removable waterproof inner liner was the killer feature for me, which was not present in Breezer 2.0 and Maze (Correct me if I am wrong). Finally, I made the decision and took my little FZ on a road trip to Cramster&rsquo;s Bangalore office yesterday to get the damn jacket. (also some balaclavas for myself and friends). I chose to ride to Bangalore instead of ordering it online since it would give me a chance to test the jacket on my way back ;) (no nagging confusion about choosing the right size as well)</p>

<p>Sorry for the soddy pics.</p>

<p><a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsc00170.jpg"><img src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsc00170.jpg?w=300" alt="The back" /></a></p>

<p><a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsc00172.jpg"><img src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/07/dsc00172.jpg?w=300" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>The Jacket is heavy in the hands but fits snuggly when I wear it. I had to wear the inner lining in Bangalore because of  the windchill in the early hours of dawn when I was leaving the city. Once the sun came out, I removed it and all was well. I am quite happy with the finish and the quality of materials that have gone into this jacket. Like most other jackets, it comes with the Cordura fabric that doesn&rsquo;t tear and 3M reflectors for added visibility to other motorists for spotting you in the dark.</p>

<h4>Verdict:</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, I have no means to compare it with others and offer a shootout of sorts since I haven&rsquo;t really tried any other jacket before. I would love to hear from the users of other jackets. If you are not a fan of an all-black jacket, DSG Maze comes in <a href="http://www.planetdsg.com/dsg-falcon-jacket-red-p-1044.html">red</a> in addition to the all-black version.</p>

<p>Ride hard and ride safe!</p>

<p>P.S: Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/sudarsanyes">Sudarsan</a> (no, not me) and Pradeep for allowing me to camp at their place for the weekend.</p>

<p>P.P.S: Thanks to my boss for buying my LCD monitor!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[24camp - Be there]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/02/10/24camp-be-there/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-10T12:19:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/02/10/24camp-be-there</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week, <a href="http://24camp.org/">24camp</a> started out as a means for people to get together and work on interesting projects/ideas.</p>

<p>Serendio will be hosting one this weekend, 13th February. We have place for about 20 &ndash; 25 in our office premises. More information can be found <a href="http://24camp.org/Camp/13Feb2010">here</a>.</p>

<p>You can also participate virtually by logging on to #24camp IRC channel on the Freenode servers. If you want to start a local, group of your own add your group in the wiki page mentioned above.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mashing Twitter and FSO]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/12/06/mashing-twitter-and-fso/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-06T14:27:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/12/06/mashing-twitter-and-fso</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really love Twitter and it didn&rsquo;t make any sense to me to shell out a rupee for every tweet sent through my Airtel Mobile. Moreover, I am on one of those monthly booster packs which allows you to send 22000 text messages for free. I simply had to exploit this by setting up my own little &lsquo;OC&rsquo; twitter forwarder written in python. (I know of smstweet.in service but I am still charged 1.50 for every tweet I send)</p>

<p>Its insanely simple to write such a &lsquo;forwarder&rsquo; in python using the services provided by the FSO (<a href="http://wiki.freesmartphone.org">freesmartphone.org</a>) Framework,</p>

<ol>
<li><p> Send messages to your old/unused number whose SIM is in the <a href="http://openmoko.com/freerunner.html">Freerunner</a> (or any other device supported by the <a href="http://wiki.freesmartphone.org">FSO</a> framework)</p></li>
<li><p> Handle the incoming messages and use <a href="http://code.google.com/p/python-twitter/">python-twitter</a> API (or) raw urllib2 to post updates. Of course, the device should be connected to the internet, you can <a href="http://wiki.openmoko.org/wiki/Usb_networking">tether</a> this device to an old unused computer. Simply put, the Freerunner should be able to access the internet.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I know this is dumb given cheap GPRS and all, but what the heck; Sundays <em>are</em> reserved for dumb things and I wanted to show off how easy it is to develop and conjure up simple but powerful scripts using open hackable hardware like the Freerunner. So take off your pedantic hats ;)</p>

<p>Here is the actual python code,</p>

<p>``` python</p>

<h1>!/usr/bin/env python</h1>

<h1>Written By Sudharshan S, <a href="http://sudharsh.wordpress.com">http://sudharsh.wordpress.com</a></h1>

<p>import dbus
import time
import logging
import twitter</p>

<p>import gobject
from gobject import MainLoop</p>

<p>from dbus.mainloop.glib import DBusGMainLoop
DBusGMainLoop (set_as_default = True)</p>

<h1>Use OAUTH?</h1>

<p>USERNAME = &ldquo;username&rdquo;
PASSWORD = &ldquo;password&rdquo;</p>

<p>log = logging.getLogger(&ldquo;TweetForwarder&rdquo;)</p>

<p>class TweetForwarder:</p>

<p>   &ldquo;&rdquo;&ldquo;Process Incoming messages and update twitter status</p>

<pre><code>  if the message startswith 'tweet'
</code></pre>

<p>   &ldquo;&rdquo;"</p>

<p>   def <strong>init</strong>(self, username, password):</p>

<pre><code>   log.warning("Starting up....")
   self.twitter_api = twitter.Api(username=username, password=password)

   # Get proxies and add signal handlers
   bus = dbus.SystemBus()
   _usage = bus.get_object("org.freesmartphone.ousaged",
                           "/org/freesmartphone/Usage")
   _proxy = bus.get_object("org.freesmartphone.ogsmd", \
                           "/org/freesmartphone/GSM/Device")
   self.usage_iface = dbus.Interface(_usage, "org.freesmartphone.Usage")
   self.usage_iface.RequestResource('GSM')
   self.sms_iface = dbus.Interface (_proxy, "org.freesmartphone.GSM.SMS")
   self.sms_iface.connect_to_signal ("IncomingMessage", self.onIncomingMessage)
</code></pre>

<p>   def onIncomingMessage(self, sender, message, kwargs):</p>

<pre><code>   log.warning("Received SMS from %s:%s" % (sender, message))
   # We don't ALL messages to this number to be tweeted
   if message.strip().startswith("tweet "):
       log.warning("Trying to update status : %s" % message[6:].strip())
       self.twitter_api.PostUpdate(message[6:])
       log.warning("Updated Status")
</code></pre>

<p>   def run(self):</p>

<pre><code>   loop = MainLoop()
   loop.run()
</code></pre>

<p>if <strong>name</strong> == &ldquo;<strong>main</strong>&rdquo;:</p>

<pre><code>logging.basicConfig()
server = TweetForwarder(USERNAME, PASSWORD)
server.run()
</code></pre>

<p>```</p>

<p>Make sure you have python-netclient and python-json installed on your Freerunner. These can be installed using the &lsquo;opkg install&rsquo; command.</p>

<p>The script and the accompanying dependency can be downloaded from <a href="http://gitorious.org/dumb-scripts/dumb-scripts/archive-tarball/master">here</a>. Just change the USERNAME and PASSWORD accordingly after scp'ing the tarball to your device.</p>

<p>Some useful links,</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
