<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bleh | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/categories/bleh/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-23T01:28:11+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost a graduate]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/03/30/almost-a-graduate/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-30T17:06:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/03/30/almost-a-graduate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>4 years ago, I joined a college which had the highest mediocrity rating among the mediocre colleges in TN. To be honest, I didn&rsquo;t have good academics in my high school, so I must say I was quite fortunate to get an undergrad &lsquo;seat&rsquo; for a CS Engineering degree there. Luckily, on the very 2nd day of college, I had enough brains to come to a conclusion that my next 4 years would be spent in an Orwellian Dystopian Parallel Universe where students wore lab coats for CS Labs. (It still beats me, the purpose of a fucking labcoat in a Theoretical Computer Science Lab).</p>

<p>Engineering education in TN is as fucked up as it gets. The fact that <strong><em>Yours Truly</em></strong> will be attending his Convocation ceremony next month and getting a degree certificate is proof enough that its fucked up beyond all recognition.</p>

<p>And did I mention, there will be 50 more new colleges this year in TN alone! Fucking Pathetic&hellip;</p>

<p>Lastly,</p>

<p>[youtube=<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDQ66r1f9M">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDQ66r1f9M</a>]</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://krishashok.wordpress.com">Krish Ashok </a>for making a joke out of us poor zombies..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Python?]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/05/11/why-python/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-11T17:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/05/11/why-python</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever had that feeling of insignificance? The feeling that your very existence is a microscopic peanut in the grand scheme of things. By grand, I mean the <a href="http://hhgproject.org/entries/wsogmm.html">Whole Sort of General Mish Mash</a>. I am going through that right now. We are, according to our own theories an extremely smart species, yet for every answer we discover, 10 more questions creep up like one of those annoying LOLCATS shouting <a href="http://icanhascheezburger.com/2009/03/02/funny-pictures-ohai-2/">&lsquo;OH HAI&rsquo;</a>. What the hell is the purpose of life? Why do we exist? What is our place in this infinite Cosmos (See the embedded video)? Its incredibly creepy even to think that our entire life is just a mega-complex probability equation, which most likely is too complex for our puny brains to comprehend.</p>

<p>{% youtube 2pfwY2TNehw&amp;hl=en&amp;fs=1 %}</p>

<p>Yeah, so basically what I am coming at is simple. Party now, Life is too short to be spent over unnecessary complications. Or in other words <strong><em>Frigging Use Python!!!!</em></strong></p>

<p>{% img center <a href="http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/python.png">http://imgs.xkcd.com/comics/python.png</a> %}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zero Productivity]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/02/01/zero-productivity/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-01T17:19:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/02/01/zero-productivity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last few weeks, my productivity has dipped to an all time low. <a href="http://programming.reddit.com/">Progit</a> is to be blamed. Suddenly I find myselves hitting refresh to see what&rsquo;s &lsquo;hot&rsquo; leading to more time reading blogs and articles, and less time actually getting some work done. So, from this point on I am activating a self-imposed ban on progit.</p>

<p>Lets see how long I last urge :D.</p>

<p><strong>EDIT: Bleh&hellip;. Gave up, ban lasted 12 minutes</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prince of the Woodland Realm]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/01/09/prince-of-the-woodland-realm/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-09T18:53:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2009/01/09/prince-of-the-woodland-realm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img center <a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/legolas1.png?w=247">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/legolas1.png?w=247</a> %}</p>

<p>{% img center <a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/out.jpeg?w=204">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2009/01/out.jpeg?w=204</a> %}</p>

<blockquote><p>Legolas Greenleaf long under tree</p>

<p>In joy thou hast lived. Beware of the Sea!</p>

<p>If thou hearest the cry of the gull on the shore,</p>

<p>Thy heart shall rest in the forest no more."</p></blockquote>

<p>My favorite character from Lord of the Rings. Not as good as the <a href="http://lotr.wikia.com/wiki/Image:Legolas1.jpg">original</a>, but I drew these after a very long time.. :)</p>

<p>I also felt like creating a <a href="http://sudharsh.deviantart.com/">deviant</a> profile for myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BhootKiddo..]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2008/06/08/bhootkiddo/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-08T20:06:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2008/06/08/bhootkiddo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>{% img center <a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/image004.jpg?w=128">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2008/06/image004.jpg?w=128</a> %}</p>

<p>As the summer holidays progress, I am finding myself become a nocturnal being. My sense of a &ldquo;day&rdquo; has changed a lot.</p>

<p>Wake up at 1200 or 1300 hours and fall asleep at around 2-3 AM, in a position as in the above photo (taken from my mobile which has a crappy camera). Back against the window, legs across my cot only to find myself waking up late in the afternoon sun with an excruciating pain in my back. Its great in a way, since both my parents leave for work early and I have the entire house to myself (na, I don&rsquo;t run around naked).</p>

<p>After waking up, the usual stuff, watch TV for a while and back to GSoC stuff..</p>

<p>Move my butt around at 5 PM to the guitar classes, return back watch Seinfeld, eat, and back to code&hellip;</p>

<p>Trust me, fixing segfaults are really fun, but I think I need to go out and play for a while&hellip; :/..I find myself lacking a <strong>life</strong> these days :(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
