<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Running | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/categories/running/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-01T21:29:46-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pebble and the Bullshit of Fitness Trackers]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2014/11/05/pebble/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-05T08:21:14-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2014/11/05/pebble</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After countless unsuccessful attempts of getting fit by waking up early in the morning and run around the neighbourhood, realisation dawned on me. I needed some extra motivation to help me get started.</p>

<p>The timing was perfect as I got that motivation (or atleast I thought I did) in the form of a very thoughtful <a href="http://getpebble.com">gift</a> from someone very special to me.</p>

<p><img class="centre" src="/images/pebble.jpg"></p>

<p>Unfortunately, my Laziness has been trouncing my Motivation without any hint of mercy whatsoever.</p>

<p>That said, I absolutely adore this little bugger of a gadget that has seamlessly merged into my daily routine.</p>

<p>Has a long battery life, is <a href="https://developer.getpebble.com/">hackable</a>, has customizable faces, syncs with my phone and has a rather nice app ecosystem.</p>

<p>However, if you are like me and somehow think that splurging money on a <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/microsoft-band/en-us">smart wearable</a> with <a href="https://jawbone.com/">sensors</a> is going to make you wake up in the morning and go do that run that you had been procastinating all along, please! Don&rsquo;t kid yourself.</p>

<p>No gadget with any fancy wizardry is going to solve the vice of Laziness. This is a challenge at a more human level.</p>

<p>A challenge that millions including me, face every morning at 6.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
