<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Life | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.me/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-12T21:16:39+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pen and Paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2014/07/12/pen-and-notebook/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-12T19:46:38+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2014/07/12/pen-and-notebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am one of those people with a very volatile memory. Unless I jot down things even if it is as mundane as getting a haircut, I find myself with a nagging sense of incompleteness in my head. It is a very uncomfortable feeling to have.</p>

<p>I had been trying to use <a href="http://evernote.com/">Evernote</a>, <a href="https://www.wunderlist.com/en/">Wunderlist</a> and <a href="http://orgmode.org/"><code>org-mode</code></a> to help solve this. No god damn luck. Only <code>org-mode</code> worked for me in the beginning but I found myself slowly starting to worry about how to format my fricking lists instead.</p>

<p>My brain had started to <a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=bikeshedding">bikeshed</a> with itself!</p>

<p>For me, these tools turned out to be hard to focus with. And lo! I fell back to using a Pen and a Notebook instead.</p>

<p><img class="centre" src="/images/notebook.jpg"></p>

<p>Writing down todo lists feels much more satisfying than typing them. The contents somehow &lsquo;sticks&rsquo; to my head and I don&rsquo;t need reminders on my phone anymore (which I mostly used to ignore anyways).</p>

<p>Of course, there are a lot of productivity problems solved successfully by software but I have come to a conclusion that simple personal todo lists is NOT one of them.</p>

<p>Pen and Paper beats the Computer in this case.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2013/05/11/i/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-11T19:37:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2013/05/11/i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>More than Death, losing my memory scares the shit out of me.
It makes me queasy to think that all the wonderful experiences I had, the secrets in my head, my tough times and failures can go poof; slowly or in an instant without warning.</p>

<p>Doesn&rsquo;t matter if its due to some fucked up illness like Alzheimer&rsquo;s or a freak accident from sheer bad luck. It is very possible that I won&rsquo;t be <em>me</em> one day.</p>

<p>The only bright side is that at least parts of my identity will live on as memories in people close to me if that happens. Coming to think of it, things won&rsquo;t be that bad after all :). As they say,</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/8x10-keep-calm-carry-on-gray.jpg?w=240">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2013/05/8x10-keep-calm-carry-on-gray.jpg?w=240</a>"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Brooks was here"]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2013/04/25/brooks-was-here/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-25T14:30:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2013/04/25/brooks-was-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Minor spoilers ahead</strong></p>

<p>Like many others I love <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0111161/">Shawshank Redemption</a>. The scene where Brooks is out of prison and is unable to catch up with the world is just plain sad. One of my favorite all time movie scenes that gives me the chills every time.</p>

<p>I keep hoping Brooks found his Freedom.</p>

<p><iframe width="" height="" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/kotNxb2YApk ?feature=player_detailpage" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chile, alla vamos!]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2011/10/01/chile-alla-vamos/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-01T13:13:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2011/10/01/chile-alla-vamos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It all started as a little hack by <a href="http://twitter.com/#%21/cnu">Srini</a> and I at the <a href="http://developer.yahoo.com/hackday/">Yahoo! Openhack</a> Event conducted in Bangalore. The hack by itself wasn&rsquo;t that fancy when compared to the other finalists but we did feel good when our hack got shortlisted for the finals. We wrote a little web app which would index <a href="http://www.delicious.com/">delicious</a> bookmarks and enable Full Text Search on the Content with a neat tagging mechanism.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, applications were open for the second round of <a href="http://www.startupchile.org/about/faqs/">StartupChile</a> program. A seed of 40K equity-free USD and an exotic location, sounded rather interesting. We added some new ideas to the original delicious hack, drafted a nice crisp application and applied a few hours before the deadline.</p>

<p>Fast forward a month, We are delighted to announce that Cruns is one of the <a href="http://www.startupchile.org/154-startups-selected-in-start-up-chiles-2nd-round-of-2011/">154 startups</a> that made it through the 2nd round of the program.</p>

<p><a href="http://startupchile.org"><img class="center" src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/sup-logo.png"></a></p>

<p>These are still early days, I am all excited, happy, anxious and scared, all the same time. Never have I budgeted for things months in advance. Ever since I passed out of college, I have been living in the relative comfort of working under a great team at Serendio where I began my baby steps as a programmer.</p>

<p>I have to admit, I am finding myself outside my comfort zone all of a sudden. Something which I hope I will adapt to sooner or later. One thing is for sure, Interesting times wait ahead :)</p>

<p>So there, Announcing Cruns; Something which we hope will help you to organize your information better.</p>

<p><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/CrunsLabs"><img class="center" src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/screenshot-11.png?w=300"></a></p>

<p>Congratulations to the other 153 teams that made it through. Looking forward to meeting you all this January!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over the Hills and not so Far Away]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/10/15/over-the-hills-and-not-so-far-away/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-15T19:29:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.me/blog/2010/10/15/over-the-hills-and-not-so-far-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had been itching to go on a motorbike roadtrip to Kerala. Sitting in the back of the car isn&rsquo;t exactly my idea of a fun and fulfilling roadtrip.</p>

<p>Therefore from Oct 2 &ndash; 10, I was on my motorbike riding through some diverse terrain and landscapes that included arid countrysides, coastal plains, villages, forests, hill stations and plantations of cardamom, sandalwood, rubber and tea.</p>

<p>The 2118 odd kilometers was done on my little 150cc Yamaha FZ16 laden with saddle bags and supplies. Given a chance, I&rsquo;d gladly re-do the same roadtrip again on a more powerful machine.</p>

<p><a href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/screenshot-111.png"><img src="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/screenshot-111.png" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>My itinerary for the trip was as follows</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Oct 2, Sat:</strong> Home &ndash; Salem &ndash; Avinashi &ndash; Coonoor</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 3, Sun:</strong> Coonoor &ndash; <em><em>crash in the mountains</em></em> &ndash; Ooty &ndash; Gudalur &ndash; Sultan Bathery (Wayanad)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 4, Mon</strong>: Sultan Bathery &ndash; Kalpetta &ndash; Calicut</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 5, Tue:</strong> Calicut &ndash; Thrissur &ndash; Chalakudi &ndash; Athirappally/Vazhachal falls</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 6, Wed:</strong> Athirapally &ndash; Unknown shortcut through rubber plantations &ndash; Kaladi &ndash; Muvattupuzha <em>(Rendezvous with my friends here and was no longer alone)</em> &ndash; Munnar</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 7, Thur</strong>: Munnar &ndash; Marayoor &ndash; Chinnar &ndash; Offroading at Anaimudi &ndash; Munnar</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 8, Fri:</strong> Munnar &ndash; Idukki &ndash; Elapara (with lots of detours taking us to awesome spots)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 9, Sat:</strong> Elapara &ndash; Vagamon &ndash; Parunthumpara &ndash; Pambanar <em>(Goodbyes over a heavy lunch and was all alone again)</em> &ndash; VandiPeriyar &ndash; Kumily &ndash; Theni &ndash; Madurai</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Oct 10, Sun:</strong> Madurai &ndash; Trichy &ndash; Home</p></li>
</ul>


<p>It was a long, wet weekend with rains lashing through Kerala rather heavily. Nevertheless, I was having lots of fun except for the crash in the mountains near Ooty. That was not fun AT ALL. Detailed logs to follow soon.</p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/dsc00470.jpg">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/dsc00470.jpg</a>"></p>

<p><img class="center <a" src="href="http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/dsc00457.jpg">http://sudharsh.files.wordpress.com/2010/10/dsc00457.jpg</a>"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
