<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: College | 42]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/categories/college/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-22T23:04:09+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Sudharshan S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Almost a graduate]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2010/03/30/almost-a-graduate/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-30T22:36:26+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2010/03/30/almost-a-graduate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>4 years ago, I joined a college which had the highest mediocrity rating among the mediocre colleges in TN. To be honest, I didn&rsquo;t have good academics in my high school, so I must say I was quite fortunate to get an undergrad &lsquo;seat&rsquo; for a CS Engineering degree there. Luckily, on the very 2nd day of college, I had enough brains to come to a conclusion that my next 4 years would be spent in an Orwellian Dystopian Parallel Universe where students wore lab coats for CS Labs. (It still beats me, the purpose of a fucking labcoat in a Theoretical Computer Science Lab).</p>

<p>Engineering education in TN is as fucked up as it gets. The fact that <strong><em>Yours Truly</em></strong> will be attending his Convocation ceremony next month and getting a degree certificate is proof enough that its fucked up beyond all recognition.</p>

<p>And did I mention, there will be 50 more new colleges this year in TN alone! Fucking Pathetic&hellip;</p>

<p>Lastly,</p>

<p>[youtube=<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDQ66r1f9M">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jpDQ66r1f9M</a>]</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://krishashok.wordpress.com">Krish Ashok </a>for making a joke out of us poor zombies..</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Exams again...:/]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/11/04/exams-again/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-04T18:09:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/11/04/exams-again</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Semesters start this friday, Nov 7th. :(. So will be missing in action for the next two weeks&hellip;..</p>

<p>Till then,</p>

<p>Ctrl-Z</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fun @ Shaastra]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/10/05/fun-shaastra/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-05T21:15:35+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/10/05/fun-shaastra</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Four words. <a href="http://www.shaastra.org/2008/">Shaastra</a> &lsquo;08 was frigging awesome. I was there a couple of days and had fun meeting people (shres, madhusudhan and many others). Also got to speak about FSO framework (slides later) as part of the FOSS sub-conference. Lots of food, some awesome talks and a wonderful atmosphere made the event memorable. Too bad, I had to leave early for the FOSS HackFest on 2nd night.</p>

<p>Only one gripe though, the event was not laptop friendly =(, It would have been awesome if the organizers had provided wifi spots near the talk venues.</p>

<p>Thanks to <a href="http://kstars.wordpress.com/">kstars</a>, <a href="http://arunchaganty.wordpress.com/">vimzard</a>, vikram and other volunteers for organizing the event .</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["What motivates you? Motivation"]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/06/02/what-motivates-you-motivation/"/>
    <updated>2008-06-02T01:09:41+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/06/02/what-motivates-you-motivation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I will be entering final year in a couple of months and this means&hellip;PLACEMENTS!!! yay! (..or the lack of it)</p>

<p>This means more &ldquo;Mock Interviews Sessions&rdquo; and &ldquo;GDs&rdquo; to &ldquo;empower&rdquo; engineering students to get placed in the only 3 software companies that exist in this physical Universe. Infosys, TCS and CTS (Apparently our college is too dumb for <em>hybrid </em>corporates like m$).</p>

<p>And this <a href="http://pravunplugged.blogspot.com/2005/03/mock-interview.html">blog post</a> sort of sums up my thoughts. Highly hilarious, rolled on the floor injuring my <em>mutti.</em></p>

<p>Especially at this,</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Any actual work experience?
Buying groceries for my neighbour who has this pretty daughter called Gayathri.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p>Oh, yeah! I can empathize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A debacle of an exam...]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/04/30/a-debacle-of-an-exam/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-30T22:04:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2008/04/30/a-debacle-of-an-exam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the Life&rsquo;s greatest ironies. I actually enjoyed studying for the Artificial Intelligence exam, one of my favourite areas. In fact an hour of my favorite anime, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ghost_in_the_shell">Ghost in the Shell: SAC</a> on monday was timed perfectly for the exam the next day.</p>

<p>But when I received the question paper, I sat there wide eyed just like the android who gets pwned by the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tachikomas">Tachikomas</a> when they attack her with the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liar_paradox">Liar Paradox</a>. A big BLEH..</p>

<p>I managed to write (in my own words and crappy handwriting), a couple of big questions and 5 short ones. To add insult to the injury, yesterday&rsquo;s paper was my personal record for the most number of pages filled in an exam; 42/44. My previous record was 34 :D.</p>

<p>On the brighter side, I may get to read Peter Norvig&rsquo;s a second time for the back paper. Well, rationalization is the solution to all of world&rsquo;s problems ;).</p>

<p>But somehow, I didn&rsquo;t feel bad about it&hellip;..<em>shit</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
