<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Politics | Anti-social]]></title>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-22T19:10:18+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Of Piracy and Social Service]]></title>
    <link href="http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2007/05/21/of-piracy-and-social-service/"/>
    <updated>2007-05-21T12:36:08+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://sudharsh.github.io/blog/2007/05/21/of-piracy-and-social-service</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Take a look at this!</p>

<p><a href="http://www.channelregister.co.uk/2007/05/18/indian_tech_vendors_protest_microsoft/">http://www.channelregister.co.uk/2007/05/18/indian_tech_vendors_protest_microsoft/</a></p>

<p>One of the many WTFs you get once in a while in the tech world. Apparently PC dealers are on a state wide bandh after getting notices from Microsoft for Piracy. And these guys are claiming that they are doing a &ldquo;service&rdquo; to the community by installing illegitimate copies of Windoze.</p>

<p>SITA or South Gujarat Information Technologists Association says, &ldquo;"Since we are are not charging anything extra for installing the software, it means that we are actually not trading in pirated software. For us this is just a sewa (selfless act) that we are offering to our customers. Besides, the pricing of their operating systems is way too high for the Indian markets.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Yup, while I agree about the pricing of M$ products..And keeping their &ldquo;Ethics&rdquo; (or the lack of it) aside, I somehow feel for M$. Whatever said, Software Piracy is akin to stealing stuff and theres no way you can defend yourself by telling that you are a doing a god damn frigging &ldquo;sewa&rdquo;. Piracy is so rampant that people think that Windoze comes free with their computers. And an association that exists, supporting these Pirates, sheesh!. If you cant afford a software, buy or use something thats Free or costs less. And even if you are using a illegitimate copy of something, just dont fucking go around telling people that you are part of a great liberation revolution or worse, claim that you are doing service to the community by distributing them.</p>

<p>Wondering, if a day will come when pimps will roam around telling that they are doing a &ldquo;sewa&rdquo; to the public. Its high time the Government steps in and stop these guys. (I do my bit when someone asks me to install winxp, I ask them to STFU.)</p>

<p>And my evil mind says that I should try it as a prank on local computer dealers.</p>

<p>And if you are someone I know and have a problem in your wretched boxes, FUCK OFF! I WONT FIX IT unless its running GNU/Linux or something legally bought.</p>

<p>Man, am I feeling a sudden urge to skin these people alive.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
